Ashley Ellis

anellis12@gmail.com github.com/anellis Durham, NC

Summary

Web Developer who enjoys exploring the possible solutions to the increasingly complex problems present in modern technology. Specializing in Ruby on Rails with additional experience in front-end development.

Web Development Skills

Languages	Ruby, JavaScript (jQuery, AJAX)
Web Frameworks	Rails 4
Testing Frameworks	Rspec, TestUnit
Databases	SQLite, PostgreSQL
Front-End	HTML5, CSS3, SASS
Version Control	Git, GitHub
Production Environments	Heroku
Methodologies	Agile, Object-Oriented Design, Test-Driven
	Development, Behavior-Driven
	Development

Education

The Iron Yard

January 2015 - April 2015

Rails Engineering

Three-month Ruby on Rails immersion bootcamp. Built real world applications
while learning new things every day related to full-stack development. From
SQL database queries to HTML, CSS and Javascript.

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

2008 - 2012

Bachelors of Arts

Notable Projects

TrialSource

- A single page application with a Rails API backend that puts agency into the hands of patients seeking trials and their physicians. TrialSource streamlines the process of identifying interventional trials with a higher likelihood of viability.
- Built with Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. Active Model Serializers for JSON formatting, attr_encrypted for database security and Geocoder for location services. Hosted on Amazon Web Services. Testing tools include RSpec and Factory Girl.

Ashley Ellis

anellis12@gmail.com github.com/anellis Durham, NC

Crash ToDo

- A ToDo application that allows users to keep track of their tasks.
- Built on a SQLite database and Ruby on Rails version 4.2.0. Devise for user authentication. AJAX and JQuery for additional functionality, SCSS, Bourbon and Neat for front-end design. Testing tools include Rspec and Factory Girl. Git version control. Hosted on Heroku.

Survey Possum

- An alternative to Survey Monkey where users can sign up to make surveys, edit them and then send the survey links to others to take the surveys.
- Built on a SQLite database and Ruby on Rails version 4.2.0, Ruby version 2.2.0.

Eat and Run

- An API that takes two basic parameters: a food and your location. It will give you
 options for nearby trails where you can go work off that food.
- Built with Ruby, Rails, SQLite, and JSON

Previous Experience

IT Applications Recruiter TEKsystems

September 2013- January 2015

Specialized in placing technical professionals within applications development including: Business Analysts, Project Managers, Datawarehouse Specialists, Technical Writers, QA Testers, and Web Developers.

Sales Representative Verizon Wireless

May 2012- September 2013

Assisted in troubleshooting mobile devices and built rapport with customers through a consultative sales process while meeting or exceeding an aggressive sales quota.